Guide to the Scottie Fitzgerald Smith Papers, 1858-1996 (bulk 1921-1986)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Scottie Fitzgerald Smith Papers
1858-1996
1921-1986
Smith, Scottie Fitzgerald
15 cubic feet (29 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Materials relating to Scottie Fitzgerald Smith's career as a journalist, her work for the Democratic Party, her personal life, and the maintenance of her parents' estates and legacies.
Biographical Note
Frances Scott "Scottie" Fitzgerald Lanahan Smith was born in 1921. She was the child of F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald. She was a graduate of Vassar College (1942), journalist, ardent supporter of the Democratic Party, and a notable figure in Washington D.C. social circles. She was married twice, first to Samuel Jackson Lanahan in 1943, with whom she had four children, and next, in 1967, to C. Grove Smith. She died in 1986 of esophageal cancer.
Chronology
1896 September 24 F. Scott Fitzgerald born to Mollie McQuillan and Edward Fitzgerald in Saint Paul, Minnesota
1900 July 24 Zelda Sayre born to Minerva Buckner "Minnie" Machen and Anthony Dickinson Sayre in Montgomery, Alabama
1920 April 3 F. Scott Fitzgerald and Zelda Sayre married
1921 October 26 Frances Scott "Scottie" Fitzgerald born in Saint Paul, Minnesota
1940 December 21 F. Scott Fitzgerald died
1942 Scottie graduated from Vassar College
1943 February Scottie and Samuel Jackson "Jack" Lanahan married
1946 April 26 Thomas Addison "Tim" Lanahan born
1948 January 25 Eleanor Anne "Bobbie" Lanahan born
1948 March 10 Zelda Fitzgerald died
1950 April 29 Samuel Jackson "Jacky" Lanahan born
1951 October Cecilia Scott Lanahan born
1967 Scottie and Samuel Jackson "Jack" Lanahan divorced
1967 Scottie and C. Grove Smith married
1973 September Scottie moved to Montgomery, Alabama
1973 October Tim Lanahan committed suicide
1980 June Scottie and C. Grove Smith divorced
1986 June 18 Scottie died of esophageal cancer in Montgomery
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, scrapbooks, photographs and clippings relating to Scottie Fitzgerald Smith's career as a journalist, her work for the Democratic Party, her personal life, and the maintenance of her parents' estates and legacies.
Access
There is some family correspondence that is currently restricted. Some of the audio recordings in the collection will require vetting before being released for research. Waivers were not signed at the time of the interviews, so unless the interviewees are deceased, they will have to give written permission for the material to be opened. The rest of the collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Related Materials
There is a 1936 letter from F. Scott Fitzgerald to "Mme. White" about Scottie Fitzgerald in the Autograph Files.
Autograph Files
Subject Headings
Names:
Bruccoli, Matthew J. (Matthew Joseph), 1931-2008; Carpenter, Liz; Chewning, Mary; Devron, Howard; Durr, Virginia Foster; Fitzgerald, F. Scott (Francis Scott), 1896-1940; Fitzgerald, Zelda, 1900-1948; Fritchey, Clayton; McGovern, George S. (George Stanley), 1922-2012; Means, Marianne
Organizations:
Harold Ober Associates; Multiple Sclerosis Association of Greater Washington; Vassar College--Students; Vassar College--Alumni and alumnae
Subjects:
Children of authors; World War, 1939-1945--Personal Narratives, American; Women journalists--United States; Journalism--Washington (D.C.); Presidents--United States--Election--1972; Democratic National Convention
Places:
Alabama--Politics and government--20th century; Washington (D.C.)--Social life and customs--20th century
Document Types:
Audiocassettes; Audiotapes; Compact discs; Correspondence; Diaries; Photographs; Realia; Scrapbooks
Titles:
Great Gatsby (Motion picture: 1974)
VCL Categories:
Family; Journalism; Literature and Writing; Politics; Vassar College
Encoding Information
Encoded by Laura Streett, October 2012. Updated 2013. Updated by Emma Gronbeck, February 2024.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Scottie's children, Eleanor, Cecilia and Samuel Lanahan, 1995.
Series List
- Series I. Biography — Paper Materials, 1858-1992
  This series includes autobiographical notes, diaries, and notebooks as well as newspaper clippings, scrapbooks and other material that document Scottie Fitzgerald Smith's personal life.
- Series II. Biography — Recordings, 1971-1995
  There are three main sections of this series: recordings of Scottie Fitzgerald Smith herself; recordings of interviews about Scottie and the extended Lanahan Family, recorded by family members; and recordings of interviews with non-family members conducted primarily by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross.
  The audio recordings in this series will require vetting before being released for research.
- Series III. School Notebooks, circa 1930s
  The School Notebooks series includes 11 volumes from Scottie's early education.
- Series IV. Correspondence, 1909-1988
  The Correspondence series is divided into four sections: Outgoing, Incoming, From Others to Others, and Invitations. The outgoing correspondence includes Scottie's letters to her husband while he was serving overseas in World War II, a large cache of letters to her daughter Eleanor, as well as letters to friends, politicians, and other family members. Of particular note are the letters she wrote as a child to her parents, her maternal grandmother, Minerva Sayre, and Santa Claus.
  The incoming correspondence includes letters from friends and family as well as a number of political figures, journalists, and other public figures. Of particular note are the letters from her paternal grandmother, Mollie Fitzgerald, her aunt, Rosalind Sayre Smith, Highland Hospital (regarding Zelda Fitzgerald), Ladybird Johnson, Adlai Stevenson, Tennessee Williams and Katharine Graham.
  The letters from others to others includes a number of letters from family and friends after Scottie's death, but it also contains older correspondence that relates to Scottie's childhood and education, and material about the Fitzgerald, Sayre and Lanahan families.
  The invitations are a telling record of the Washington social/political scene in the 1950s and 1960s. Most events were fundraisers for political or social causes, but some were smaller get-togethers for Scottie's circle of friends and acquaintances.
  The Lanahan Family correspondence in Box 24 is restricted.
- Series V. Writings, 1935-1984
  This series includes a large number of Scotties writings, in a variety of formats. Some include notes and drafts, and others are merely clippings. One particular value of having so many of her writings contained in this collection is that she published under so many different names it would be difficult to compile a complete bibliography. This series should include some version of most if not all of the major pieces she produced.
- Series VI. F. Scott and Zelda Fitzgerald, 1937-1996
  Scottie spent a good deal of time dealing with the estates, literary and artistic rights, and legacies of both her parents. This series includes three sections: one on each of her parents and one on the issues that related to them as a couple. Much of the material in this series is related to the 1974 film version of The Great Gatsby.
- Series VII. Political Activities and Interests, 1956-1980
  Series VII includes material relating to Scottie's political work, particularly her support of various Democrats in political races. A large section of this series relates to George McGovern's 1972 run for President (including recorded interviews with Lester and Helen Hyman and a recording of an event celebrating the Grassroots Grasshopper train tour), but there is also information about her earlier work in the 1950s and 1960s as well as her involvement in Alabama politics after she moved there in 1973.
- Series VIII. Musical Theater and Skits, circa 1938-1988
  Scottie took an interest in musical theater in college and continued to use her skills for skits for various fundraising events, particularly for the Multiple Sclerosis Association of Greater Washington. This series includes a scrapbook, programs, sheet music, and also recordings of various performances.
- Series IX. Photographs, 1920-1985
  The photographs include four albums and a number of loose photographs. The "Family Album" in boxes 20 and 21 was rehoused for preservation purposes, but the original order and annotations have been preserved in a set of photocopies housed in box 20.
- Series X. Miscellaneous, circa 1951-1973
  The "miscellaneous" materials include files that didn't fit into any of the previous series, including a number of recordings Scottie made while working on the history and geography of the American South.
- Series XI. Unprocessed Additions, 1957-1979
Container List
- Series I. Biography — Paper Materials
  - Notebook No. 1, Part 1 — "Babies,", circa 1946-1949 (Folder 1.1)
  - Notebook No. 1, Part 2 — College notes, circa 1938-1942 (Folder 1.2)
  - Notebook No. 1, Part 3 — List of wedding presents, 1943 (Folder 1.3)
  - Notebook No. 2 — Mix of diary and finances, circa 1940-1963 (Folder 1.4)
  - Diaries, 1945-1946; (2 volumes) (Folder 1.5)
  - Diary and financial record, 1951; (1 volume) (Folder 1.6)
  - Diary — Paris, circa 1980s; (1 volume) (Folder 1.7)
  - Autobiographical notes — "Reflections on December 31, 1968" (Folder 1.8)
  - Autobiographical notes — "Log of Events: The Visit of Cecilia L. Kehn to Montgomery Alabama, January 1979" (Folder 1.9)
  - Autobiographical notes, 15 Aug 1984 (Folder 1.10)
  - Autobiographical notes — "Notes from Grove Smith's Ramblings,", undated (Folder 1.11)
  - Memoir/Diary, 1985-1986; (1 bound and 1 photocopied typescript) (Folder 1.12)
  - Miscellaneous notes about vacations and summers, 1953-1984, undated (Folder 1.13)
  - Travel journals from Europe trip with Mary Janney and Dede Goodhue, July 1973 (Folder 1.14)
  - Datebook, 1959 (Folder 1.15)
  - Datebook, 1962 (Folder 1.16)
  - Datebooks, 1964-1966; (3 volumes) (Folders 1.17 - 1.19)
  - Datebooks, 1968-1972; (5 volumes) (Folders 1.20 - 1.24)
  - Datebook, 1976 (Folder 1.25)
  - Calendar page, Nov 1984 (Folder 1.26)
  - Clippings — General, 1920s; (2 clippings) (Folder 23.3)
  - Clippings — General, 1939-1992, undated; (9 folders) (Folders 4.1 - 4.9)
  - Clippings — "The Spell of Scott Fitzgerald Grows Stronger," Life, 16 Feb 1959; (complete magazine) (Box 6)
  - Clippings — Article by Winzola McLendon, Ladies Home Journal, Nov 1974 (Folder 1.27)
  - Clippings — Obituaries, 1986 (Folder 4.10)
  - Memorials, 1986, 1992; (photocopies) (Folder 1.28)
  - Funeral attendance book, 1986 (Folder 1.29)
  - Scrapbook — Zelda's scrapbook about Scottie, circa 1920-1943; [partial] (Box 13)
  - Scrapbook — General, 1934-1938 (Box 14)
  - Scrapbook — General, 1939-1940 (Box 15)
  - Scrapbook — General (including F. Scott Fitzgerald obituaries), 1940-1941 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook — General, 1942-1943 (Box 25)
  - Scrapbook — Mostly MS skits, 1953-1956 (Box 16)
  - Scrapbook — Politics, 1956 (Box 17)
  - Scrapbook — Travel, 1964-1965 (Box 18)
  - Family — Children — Miscellaneous (Folder 1.30)
  - Family — Children — Clippings (Folder 4.11)
  - Family — Samuel Jackson Lanahan — Clippings (Folder 4.12)
  - Friends and extended family — Clippings (Folder 4.13)
  - Genealogy and extended family (Folder 1.31)
  - Genealogy and extended family — Letter from [Eliza Scott to Elizabeth R. K. Elder], Glen Mary Farm, 1858 (Folder 23.1)
  - Genealogy and extended family — Unidentified letter from a Scott or Fitzgerald relative, Glen Mary Farm, 24 July 1876 (Folder 23.2)
  - Genealogy and extended family — See also "The Colonial Ancestors of Francis Scott Key Fitzgerald" (1981) and "The Maryland Ancestors of Zelda Sayre Fitzgerald" (1983) in Series IV: Writings.
  - Alabama Senior Citizens Hall of Fame Medal of Honor, 1988 (Folder 6.1)
  - Finances — Brookville Road House, circa 1950 (Folder 1.32)
  - Finances — Bank book, 1950-1951 (Folder 1.33)
  - Finances — General, 1953 (Folder 1.34)
  - Finances — Minerva Sayre's estate, 1958 (Folder 4.14)
  - Finances — Trapeze Shop, 1964, 1969, undated (Folder 4.15)
  - Finances — Nonquitt Property, Massachusetts, 1982-1983 (Folder 4.16)
  - Finances — Plans for Nonquitt House, with letter to Bobbie, 1982 (Box 25)
  - Finances — Miscellaneous, 1941-1986 (Folder 1.35)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 1.36)
- Series II. Biography —Recordings
  - Recordings of FSFLS
    - FSFLS interviewed by David Yellin and two others on a Memphis television panel show called "Face to Face." She was asked about Don't Quote Me but also her childhood, being the daughter of Zelda and F. Scott Fitzgerald, Nancy Milford's book, life in Washington versus the South, and the role of women in politics, 16 January 1971; (26:39) (Box 10 - CD 1 (Reel 1))
    - FSFLS and Samuel Jackson Lanahan — Lanahan and Fitzgerald genealogy (Interviewed by Eleanor and Jacky Lanahan), 2 June 1986; (minutes 1-36) (Box 11 - CD 2 (Tape 1 side a))
    - FSFLS — her papers and finances, Tim Lanahan (Interviewed by Eleanor and Jacky Lanahan), 2 June 1986; (35:12) (Box 11 - CD 3 (Tape 1 side b))
    - FSFLS — her family life, writing, and political work in the 1940s and 1950s (Interviewed by Cecilia Ross), June 1986; (23:14) (Box 11 - CD 4 (Tape 2 side a))
    - FSFLS — her writing, political work, musicals, and the Washington social scene in the 1950s and 1960s, also her relationship with Clayton Fritchey and family life with Grove Smith (Interviewed by Cecilia Ross), 11 June 1986; (23:31) (Box 11 - CD 5 (Tape 2 side b))
    - FSFLS — her family life, writing, musicals, political activities and the Washington social scene in the 1960s and 1970s, as well as her move to Alabama, and the growth of interest in F. Scott Fitzgerald's work, (Interviewed by Cecilia Ross and George Alfred Browning), June 1986; (47:30) (Box 11 - CD 6 (Tape 3 side a))
    - FSFLS — writing and political work in Alabama in the 1970s, her relationship with her grandchildren, Trapeze, her feelings about the South (Interviewed by Cecilia Ross), June 1986; (minutes 1-23) (Box 11 - CD 7 (Tape 3 side b))
    - Transcript of Interview of FSFLS by Cecilia Lanahan, June 1986 (Folder 1.37)
  - Recordings about FSFLS and the Extended Lanahan Family by Family
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky" — his life and family events in the 1960s and early 1970s (Interview by Eleanor Lanahan), 13 January 1988; (32:09 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 8 (Tape 4 side a))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky" — his life and family events during the 1970s, and Tim's suicide (Interview by Eleanor Lanahan), 13 January 1988; (24:12 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 8 (Tape 4 side b))
    - Lanahan, Eleanor and Cecilia and Chris Ross — current politics, books, art, and parenting, 1992; (31:14 - track 2 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 9 (Tape 5 side a))
    - Lanahan, Eleanor and Cecilia and Chris Ross — parenting, FSFLS's feelings about pornography and gambling, her temper tantrums, Sheila Lanahan, and other family history, 1992; (28:29 - track 1 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 9 (Tape 5 side b))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky" and Eleanor Lanahan — using photographs to clarify the family chronology, particularly Jacky's life and family vacations, and discussion of potential changes to the Scottie manuscript, 13 January 1995; (46:38 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 10 (Tape 6 side a))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky" and Eleanor Lanahan — Jacky's relationship with Jack Lanahan and their parents' quarrels over money, 13 January 1995; (16:04 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 10 (Tape 6 side b))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — discussion of discrepancies of perspective on Jacky's early life and the Lanahan family dynamic, 14 January 1995; (46:41 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 11 (Tape 7 side a))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — continued discussion of how the Lanahan household functioned, the role of alcohol, discrepancies between memories, and clearing up the chronology, 14 January 1995; (46:42 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 12 (Tape 7 side b))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — continued discussion of how the Lanahan household functioned, the role of alcohol, and an au pair who joined the family in 1964, 15 January 1995; (45:54 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 13 (Tape 8 side a))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — their education, other childcare help, alcoholism, their parents' love affairs, and Jack Lanahan's parenting, 15 January 1995; (45:56 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 14 (Tape 8 side b))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — Eleanor's romantic relationships, religion, a summary of the discussions and agreements they'd made in the previous conversations, and talk about family vacations, 15 January 1995; (45:41 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 15 (Tape 9))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — pleasant times from their family life, their step-sister, and their parenting techniques, 15 January 1995; (23:55 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 16 (Tape 10))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jacky," Cecilia Lanahan Ross and Eleanor Lanahan — money, 16 January 1995; (4:01 - recorded at a restaurant) (Box 11 - CD 17 (Tape 11))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack" — Meeting FSFLS, their early relationship, and marriage (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan, Cecilia Ross [and Chris Ross?]), July 1994; (41:16) (Box 11 - CD 18 (Tape 12))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack" — his education, how he met FSFLS, his family background and the whiskey business, and his early career (Interview by Eleanor Lanahan), circa 1980s; (24:56 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 19 (Tape 13))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack" — Lanahan genealogy, his childhood, the staffing of his childhood home, and his early relationship with FSFLS (Interview by Eleanor Lanahan), February 1988; (46:57 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 20 (Tape 14 side b))
    - Lanahan, Samuel Jackson "Jack" — his childhood (Interview by Eleanor Lanahan), February 1988; (minutes 1-5 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 21 (Tape 14 side a))
    - Smith, C. Grove and Martin — Grove's relationship with FSFLS as well as her relationship with Clayton Fritchey, her role as a grandmother, and her political work with Grove (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1988; (minutes 5-36) (Box 11 - CD 21 (Tape 14 side a))
    - Smith, C. Grove and Martin — how Grove and FSFLS met, and how their children interacted with each other and their parents (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1988; (31:45) (Box 11 - CD 22 (Tape 15 side a))
    - Smith, C. Grove and Martin — FSFLS's move to Alabama and the end of her marriage to Grove, alcohol, FSFLS's cancer and final days. Morella, the Smith's housekeeper, also sat down and talked about her impressions of FSFLS (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1988; (31:45) (Box 11 - CD 22 (Tape 15 side b))
    - Smith, C. Grove and Martin — Morella continued with her reminiscences. Discussion of FSFLS's final illness and cleaning out her house, her political work in the 1960s and 1970s, and the political atmosphere in Washington during that era (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1988; (45:49) (Box 11 - CD 23 (Tape 16 side a))
    - Smith, C. Grove and Martin — Tim Lanahan's life after Vietnam, the Smith/Lanahan children's drug use, a family trip to Nantucket in 1968, and Poupette's relationship with the family (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), 1988; (45:46) (Box 11 - CD 24 (Tape 16 side b))
    - Miles, Eleanor Lanahan — Lanahan genealogy, Samuel Jackson Lanahan's childhood and his relationship with FSFLS (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan), 10 Feb 1988; (31:40 and 15:49 - phone interview) (Box 11 - CD 25 (Tape 17))
    - Birthday celebration including several members of the Fitzgerald side of the family, including discussions of the Fitzgeralds, Delihants and Taylors, circa 1980s; (47:01 and 13:19) (Box 11 - CD 26 (Tape 18))
  - Interviews with others about FSFLS
    - APRIL 1987 TRIP TO ALABAMA
      - Henrietta McGuire — About FSFLS's life in Montgomery and her membership in "Women of America" (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), April 1987; (42:51) (Box 11 - CD 27 (Tape 19 side a))
      - Pattillo, Edward "Eddie" — About FSFLS's life in Montgomery and friendship with Pattillo (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), April 1987; (42:31) (Box 11 - CD 28 (Tape 19 side b))
      - Pattillo, Edward "Eddie" — about his friendship with FSFLS when she returned to Montgomery (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan, Cecilia Ross, and Dodgie Shaffer), April 1987; (minutes 1-43) (Box 11 - CD 29 (Tape 20 side a))
      - Steiner, Katherine — about her childhood friendship with Zelda and later friendship with FSFLS when she returned to Montgomery (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan, Cecilia Ross, Dodgie Shaffer and Eddie Pattillo), April 1987; (minutes 43-47) (Box 11 - CD 29 (Tape 20 side a))
      - Steiner, Katherine — about her childhood friendship with Zelda and later friendship with FSFLS when she returned to Montgomery (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan, Cecilia Ross, Dodgie Shaffer and Eddie Pattillo), April 1987; (minutes 1-41) (Box 11 - CD 30 (Tape 20 side b))
      - Dinner party thrown by Dot Moore in Montgomery, includes reminiscences by Dot as well as Jake and Judy Wagner about FSFLS's political activities (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), April 1987; (minutes 41-46) (Box 11 - CD 30 (Tape 20 side b))
      - Dinner party thrown by Dot Moore in Montgomery, includes reminiscences by Dot as well as Jake and Judy Wagner about FSFLS's political activities (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), April 1987; (46:17) (Box 11 - CD 31 (Tape 21 side a))
      - Dinner party thrown by Dot Moore in Montgomery, includes reminiscences by Dot as well as Jake and Judy Wagner about FSFLS's political activities (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), April 1987; (46:05) (Box 11 - CD 32 (Tape 21 side b))
    - JUNE 1987 TRIP TO ALABAMA
      - Stapp, Mary Lee, Tom Conner and Waverly Barbe - Dinner party (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (45:53) (Box 11 - CD 33 (Tape 22 side a))
      - Stapp, Mary Lee, Tom Conner and Waverly Barbe - Dinner party (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (11:59) (Box 11 - CD 34 (Tape 22 side b))
      - Shaffer, Dodgie (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (minutes 1-25) (Box 11 - CD 35 (Tape 23 side a))
      - Carmichael, Malcolm — re Grove Smith and FSFLS's divorce (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (minutes 25-37) (Box 11 - CD 35 (Tape 23 side a))
      - Garland, Julia — about childhood in Montgomery and the Sayres (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (minutes 37-46) (Box 11 - CD 35 (Tape 23 side a))
      - Garland, Julia — about childhood in Montgomery and the Sayres (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan, Cecilia Ross, Dodgie Shaffer and Tom Conners), June 1987; (minutes 1-21) (Box 11 - CD 36 (Tape 24 side a))
      - [Dodgie?] on St. Cecilia's Chapel (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (minutes 21-26) (Box 11 - CD 36 (Tape 24 side a))
      - Lunch at Elite with Dodgie, Dot Moore, and Henrietta McGuire about FSFLS's political work (Interviewed by Eleanor Lanahan and Cecilia Ross), June 1987; (minutes 26-46 (Box 11 - CD 36 (Tape 24 side a))